americanexpressindia.co.in 2019-03-07

# American Express | India Online Privacy Statement

If you have questions about our online privacy statement or want to make a complaint, call us at the number on the back of your Card or at the following: 

### Glossary

 **Aggregated Information ** \-- data or information relating to multiple people which has been combined or aggregated. Aggregated Information includes information that we create or compile from various sources, including card transactions or certain data from Cookies and Similar Technologies. 

**American Express (we, our, us) ** \-- the American Express Company as identified at the beginning of this online privacy statement. 

**American Express Family of Companies ** \-- any affiliate and subsidiary of, and any company owned or controlled by, the American Express Company. 

**Business Partners ** \-- any third parties with whom we conduct business and have a contractual relationship, such as a business that accepts American Express branded cards 

**Co-brand Partners ** \-- businesses we partner with to offer cards featuring both brand logos. 

**Cookies and Similar Technologies ** \-- a _cookie_ is a small data file that a website transfers to your computer's hard drive. We may place cookies when you visit our website or another company’s website where our ads appear or when you make purchases, request or personalize information, or register for certain services. If you accept the cookies used on our website, websites that are “powered by” another company on our behalf, or websites where our ads appear, you may give us access to information about your interests. We may use that information to personalize your experience. Similar technologies such as web beacons, pixels, gifs, and tags also do the same thing. We use the term Cookies and Similar Technologies in this statement to refer to all technologies that collect information in this way. 

**De-identified Information ** \-- data or information used in a way that does not identify you to a third party. We often derive De-Identified Information from Personal Information/SPI. It includes information that we may collect from various sources, such as card transactions or certain data from Cookies and Similar Technologies. 

**IP Address ** \-- a number assigned to a device when connecting to the Internet. 

**Online Information ** \-- data or information collected on the American Express websites and apps as well as on websites and apps of third parties relating to topics about our business which may include Personal Information/SPI, Aggregated Information and De-Identified Information. 

**Other Information ** \-- American Express internal information (for example, Card transaction data), external data that financial companies use to process applications and complete transactions, and other online and offline information we collect from or about you. 

**Our Privacy Principles ** \-- For a copy of the American Express Privacy Policy, [which covers both online and other information, [click here](http://www.americanexpress.com/india/pdfs/privacy_statement.pdf). 

**Personal Information or Personal Identifiable Information” (PII) ** \-- means any information that relates to a natural person, which, either directly or indirectly, in combination with other information available or likely to be available with a body corporate, is capable of identifying such person. 

**Sensitive Personal Data or Information (SPI) ** \-- includes Personal Information that also consists of information relating to: 

  * Passwords
  * Financial information such as Bank account or credit card or debit card or other payment instrument details
  * Physical, physiological and mental health condition
  * Sexual orientation
  * Medical records and history
  * Biometric information

Sensitive Personal Data or Information does not include information that is freely available or accessible in the public domain or furnished under the Right to Information Act, 2005 or any other law for the time being in force. 

**Service Providers ** \-- any vendor, third party and/or company that performs business operations on our behalf, such as printing, mailing, and other communications services (email, direct mail, etc.), marketing, data processing, servicing, collections, or ad management. 

**Targeted Advertising ** \-- ads we, or our Service Providers, display on websites outside the American Express Family of Companies based on the preferences or interests inferred from data collected from a particular computer or device regarding web viewing behaviors over time and across different websites. 

**Third-Party Ad-Servers ** \-- companies that provide the technology to place ads on websites (and apps) and track how ads perform. These companies may also place and access cookies on your device. The information they collect from our websites is in a form that does not identify you personally.
